<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 16:36:01 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 16:36:01 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why I&#39;m Not a Vegetarian</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am an omnivore by choice. I feel that I shouldn’t discriminate against particular foods a priori. I should try them and then decide for myself. That, of course, doesn’t mean I don’t have a preference. I love goat’s cheese, I really, really, &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; hate raisins, and I could eat Nutella for the rest of my life. And there is no unique explanation for why I like the foods I like – sometimes their taste, texture, or smell is divine, other times I like the eating rituals, and now and then I go for something sentimental, e.g. those dubious fish-shaped chocolate cakes I used to pick up on the way home from school. What’s more, my taste preference is not uniquely determined by my taste buds: there may be genetic predispositions involved, but what I ate in my early childhood certainly influenced me as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Political, environmental, and animal rights issues inform our choices as ethical consumers. Thanks to the insistent education of my friends, I began to eat less meat, in fact so little that &lt;em&gt;extensionally&lt;/em&gt;, you might call me a vegetarian. And to promote social change, as they say, you should advocate your vegetarianism. So when asked about dietary requirements, we should always stand up to our carni-normative society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I do not self-identify as a vegetarian. To be clear: I am not a strict vegetarian. Occasionally, I get drawn to sushi and schawarmas. But many vegetarians are not strict with themselves; as I pointed out, the point of calling yourself a vegetarian is not always to make sure you get served what you want (anyone who has tasted a spinach and filo pie will agree). It is to act against our irresponsible eating behaviour. So why don’t I join in on the cause?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Short answer: calling yourself a vegetarian means you accept the distinction between carnivores and vegetarians, and everything that is attached to that distinction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long answer: there are good reasons to refuse the vegetarian label.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, it’s unwise, as the label comes with bad associations. To meat eaters, you are too quickly dismissed as an animal-loving hippie. Moreover, it often comes across as a provocation. How often has your dietary requirements sparked a dinner conversation on the ethics of killing animals? Even if you are not a moralising person, your label alone with make people feel uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, people sometimes fail to realise that vegetarianism is a complex phenomenon. Sure, there are many animal-loving people out there (and there’s nothing wrong with that: Nietzsche once said that a society’s attitude towards animals is the most telltale reflection of its morality). But there are other reasons as well: taste (“kale is delicious”), health (“you can live on coconuts“), environmental (“the meat industry is a massive waste of water”), political (“we must boycott fast food monopolies”), even social (“vegetarians are cool people”). So the reasons for being a vegetarian are plentiful, and the label is inevitably simplifying matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More importantly, there are more ways to categorise food. There’s sweet and savoury, fast and slow, things containing goat’s cheese, local produce, organic, genetically modified, things born out of happy chickens… Some categories may have an ethical dimension, others are purely aesthetic. It seems that the categorisation of “with meat” vs. “without meat” is just too narrow-minded. We need to allow for food pluralism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what I’m saying is this: creating a vegetarian subculture will not help fight against the carni-normative attitude. It’s better to be a pragmatist and refuse the label. Instead, we will speak out about our food preferences, and our reasons for them. This is the most consistent way to promote social change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My next post will be on a completely unrelated topic: why are so many lesbians vegetarians?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was born out of the marriage equality debate earlier this year. Here’s a link to &lt;a href=&quot;http://http//www.againstequality.org/about/marriage/&quot;&gt;the &amp;gt; campaign&lt;/a&gt;, and here’s a &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.practicalethics.ox.ac.uk/2012/01/can-you-be-gay-by-choice/&quot;&gt;very good analysis&lt;/a&gt; of the “gay by choice” dialectic. And yes, I am aware that carnivores also eat vegetables, so my analogy isn’t perfect. But hopefully it was entertaining.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Update: Based on the feedback I heard from my handful of readers, the message of this blog post was lost. I apologise. Please read it again and see how far you can take the food and sex analogy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/food/lgbt/gender/2014/09/15/vegetarian/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/food/lgbt/gender/2014/09/15/vegetarian/</guid>
        
        
        <category>food</category>
        
        <category>LGBT</category>
        
        <category>gender</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Homemade Bubble Tea Recipe</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Bubble tea (珍珠奶茶) in the streets – if indeed you can find a store these days – has a bad reputation: the colourful bubbles, combined with artificial flavourings and milk powder kept in large, unlabelled containers, look distinctly carcinogenic. Luckily for me, I am a fan of the traditional milk tea with tapioca pearls (vegetarian, in case you were wondering). But with over 3€ a cup, it’s not something a student can afford to drink every other day. And if you are like me and very picky about the quality, you will want to know how to produce your perfect cup of bubble tea at home. Here’s how I do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For roughly 4 cups of bubble tea…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;you-will-need&quot;&gt;You Will Need&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;100g dried tapioca pearls (available only in bigger Asian/Taiwanese supermarkets, for less than 2€)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;50g molasses sugar (available in organic supermarkets, 2-3€ for 500g)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tea bags, any kind of black tea will do (I’m using Cafédirect’s Hand-picked Tea, £2.50 for 80 tea bags)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;100ml cream&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;0.75-1 l milk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;some water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;some sugar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;equipment&quot;&gt;Equipment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Saucepan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bowl/cup/jar for the pearls&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Measuring cups&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Strainer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Whisk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bubble Tea straws (£2.40 for 100)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;instructions&quot;&gt;Instructions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cook the tapioca pearls&lt;/strong&gt;: Boil about 0.75 l of water in a saucepan, and then add the pearls (you will end up with a mush otherwise). Turn the heat to medium and cook the pearls for about 40 minutes. Keep stirring now and then, preferably with a whisk. The pearls are ready when they are completely soft inside. Remove the pan from heat, cover, and let the pearls sit for another 10-15 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quenching and sweetening&lt;/strong&gt;: Put the molasses into your bowl/cup/jar (I use mason jars to preserve the leftover pearls). The molasses will give it a more interesting taste, and its syrupy texture keeps the pearls moist. When the pearls are done, rinse them in a strainer with cold water – this ensures the chewiness. Then add them to your jar of sugar, and stir until the sugar has melted completely. Set aside to cool.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prepare the tea&lt;/strong&gt;: The simplest way to do it is to make a strong cup of tea, let it cool, and then add some milk. But I’ve noticed that the original Taiwanese milk tea is much creamier than your ordinary cup of British tea. So I would suggest the following:
Boil some water (perhaps 100ml), add it to your tea of choice, and let it cook for 2-3 minutes. Then add some milk and cream, according to you own taste. My finished tea had roughly 4/5 milk, 1/10 cream and 1/10 water. I added 2 spoons of sugar, which was just right for me. Cook until it boils, and then remove from heat.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Serving&lt;/strong&gt;: If you like hot bubble tea, simply take a forth of the pearls and add your freshly made milk tea. If you prefer to drink it cold, then let it cool for about an hour. You can make it extra-chilly by putting the milk tea in a cocktail shaker. Add a few ice cubes and shake for 20 seconds, then pour into a tall glass and add the pearls. Et voilà!
Finished!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Finished!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;NB&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The straw problem.&lt;/strong&gt; It is a little awkward drinking bubble tea with a spoon. Think ahead and keep your old straws, or ask nicely at your bubble tea store… I ended up buying some from &lt;a href=&quot;https://flapperleenie.wordpress.com/www.creamsupplies.co.uk/jumbo-fat-straws-12mm-pack-of-100/prod_6656.html&quot;&gt;Cream Supplies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Variations?&lt;/strong&gt; As is probably clear by now, I’m a purist and hate those silly balls in poisonous green liquids. Although I’m really happy with my current bubble tea supply, I can imagine altering the flavour of the milk tea. How about chai tea latte or mocha powder as the base of the milk tea? Or try adding a little Amaretto or Baileys for those cold winter days…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/food/2014/01/30/bubbletea/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/food/2014/01/30/bubbletea/</guid>
        
        
        <category>food</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Geach&#39;s Song: a Transcription</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Judging by the fact that not even one sudoku has been posted here in the last year, non-believers might say that my blog has officially died. Well, shun the non-believers! Here’s an attempt to resurrect it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was very sad to hear that Peter Geach died recently. Last year, Leiter Reports posted a &lt;a href=&quot;http://leiterreports.typepad.com/blog/2013/05/geach-sings-about-frege-russell-and-wittgenstein-.html&quot;&gt;recording&lt;/a&gt; of Geach singing his version of the Lorelei (written by Heinrich Heine, set to music by Friedrich Silcher). I transcribed the German lyrics for those who are curious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ich weiß nicht, was soll es bedeuten
&lt;br /&gt;Dass ich so traurig bin
&lt;br /&gt;Denn Frege auf manchen Seiten
&lt;br /&gt;Erklärte es sei doch ein Sinn
&lt;br /&gt;Die Angst wirkt schwer und es dunkelt
&lt;br /&gt;Und nichtet, nichtet das Nein
&lt;br /&gt;Das gold’ne Gebirge funkelt
&lt;br /&gt;Im tiefsten Außersein&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ein rundes Viereck blitzet
&lt;br /&gt;Darüber wunderbar
&lt;br /&gt;Der König von Frankreich sitzet
&lt;br /&gt;Und kämmt sein einziges Haar
&lt;br /&gt;Mit einem einzahnigen Kamme
&lt;br /&gt;Und singt ein Lied dabei
&lt;br /&gt;Das hat eine ganz seltsame
&lt;br /&gt;Störspannende Melodei&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Der Frege im kleinen Schiffe
&lt;br /&gt;Erhört es mit wildem Weh
&lt;br /&gt;Er sieht nicht die Widerspruchsriffe
&lt;br /&gt;Er starrt nur hinauf in die Höh’
&lt;br /&gt;Ich glaube die Wellen verschlingen
&lt;br /&gt;Am Ende Frege und Kahn
&lt;br /&gt;Und das hat mit seinem Singen
&lt;br /&gt;Herr Wittgenstein getan!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/philosophy/logic/music/2014/01/20/geach/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/philosophy/logic/music/2014/01/20/geach/</guid>
        
        
        <category>philosophy</category>
        
        <category>logic</category>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>It ain&#39;t necessarily so...</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“It ain’t necessarily so…” is one of the most memorable songs from the Gershwin opera Porgy and Bess. Apart from raising serious doubts about the stories one finds in the Bible, I think it also provides an excellent title for this brand-new, super-fresh, and certainly mind-blowing blog on philosophy and living with philosophy. As to the form and content of this blog: I haven’t a clue. I will simply let it live for a while and see where it takes me. If all things fail, sudokus shall be published on a weekly basis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/philosophy/music/2013/01/20/welcome/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/philosophy/music/2013/01/20/welcome/</guid>
        
        
        <category>philosophy</category>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
